Lyla S. Taguma

(+44) 7367863686 London, UK

lyla.taguma@gmail.com

LinkedIn | GitHub

NEUROSCIENCE GRADUATE · ASPIRING FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Advocate of interdisciplinary collaboration & open-source software solutions.

Curious by nature, possessing a discerning eye for aesthetics and attentiveness to detail.

Passionate about crafting seamless digital experiences to practise UI design with improved accessibility.

Thrilled to apply skills & knowledge to address real-world problems in a creative & innovative environment.

Skills

React On TypeScript On Procreate On Bootstrap, Tailwind, SCSS On RESTful APIs

Node.js
 JavaScript
 Figma & Miro
 Bash, Terminal workflow
 Adobe Illustrator / Inkscape
 Next.js
 PostgreSQL
 Python / R
 Git / GitHub version control
 statistics, hypothesis testing

Other Languages English native proficiency

Japanese native proficiency

French conversational, reading & writing proficiency

Major Projects

Next.js Web-Application Personal Portfolio Website

2024 Vercel & React.js

London, UK

Built a portfolio (https://lysts.vercel.app/) in Next.js to learn the latest React.js optimisations using TypeScript,
 CSS, Framer Motion, Resend, and more. Includes a contact form, a simplistic interface, and subtle animations.

Undergraduate Research Oestrous Cycle Dependent Modulation of Cortical & Hippocampal Formation Activity

2023 The Rochefort Lab, Centre for Discovery Brain Sciences Edinburgh, UK

 Drove analysis and visualisation of brain activity data obtained using cutting-edge neural recording techniques in mice using Python. Collaborated & presented with professional neuroscientists, informaticians, technicians.

Game Development & Design Artist Role

2022 – 2023 Independent Groups (Ludum Dare, itch.io)

Edinburgh, UK

Teamed up with UX/UI/sound designers and game programmers, globally. Gained familiarity with FMOD and Unity. Used Procreate & Adobe Illustrator for art. Advised storyline and UX/UI changes to elevate product.

Treasurer (Executive Committee Board Member) & Librarian

2020 – 2023 Edinburgh University String & Chamber Orchestra

Edinburgh, UK

 Analysed and managed finances (e.g., tour expenses); brought a society out of debt during COVID-19, raising annual revenue by 6-fold over the last 3 years. Organised, distributed, and archived music score libraries.

HP Mars Home Planet Competition, Global Shortlist Qualifiers

2018 Hewlett Packard

Japan

 Conceptualised, designed, and nationally presented sustainable and energy-efficient transportation solutions for human life envisioned on Mars, in collaboration with Kaisei Academy (KIA) & Toshima-gaoka Academy.

Education & Certifications

Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp Full-Stack Development Course by Dr. Angela Yu

2023 - 2024 Udemy Platform

London (remote), UK

Practised full-stack engineering tools: CSS Bootstrap, React.js, JavaScript/TypeScript logic, design concepts,
 SQL/PostgreSQL, authentication, firebase, Git/GitHub, Postman/REST/APIs, and Bash. Certification received.

Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Sciences, Neuroscience Honours

2019 – 2023 The University of Edinburgh, College of Medicine & Veterinary Medicine

Edinburgh, UK

Certified in animal care and surgery. Explored biomedicine, biology, biochemistry, and anatomy/development.

Middle & High School Diploma, Academic Merit Award, AP Scholar Award

2011 – 2019 The International School of the Sacred Heart

Tokyo, Japan

Advanced Placement in English Language & Composition, Calculus AB, Calculus BC, French Language,
 Chemistry, and Biology. Awarded for achieving grades above A- in 70% or more of subjects taken. Awarded in Fine Arts for contributions to choral and orchestral scenes.

Employment Experience

Freelance Artist & Composer

2019 – 2024 Self-employed Service

(remote) International

- Provided interface design ideas & graphical elements (e.g. favicons). Currently working on artwork for a
 podcast on addiction science and a start-up in protein research based in Seattle, Washington.
- Composed, recorded, and mixed for a film track commission for Bournemouth filmmakers using Reaper.

Academic & Fine Arts Tutor

2018 – 2022 Self-employed Service

Japan & UK

Covered a wide range of academics & music for youths with personalised action plans or violin/music lessons.

Instructor & Teaching Assistant for Tokyo Metro

2018 – 2022 Tokyo Metro

Tokyo, Japan

• Created interactive guidance sessions and educational films engaging Tokyo Metro employees in preparation for the 2020 Tokyo Olympics. Resolved nuanced English translation issues, improving customer satisfaction.

Financial Advisor, Marketing, & Personal Assistant

2019 – 2020 Tokyo Sinfonia, Internship

Tokyo, Japan

• Evaluated and identified financial shortcomings and long-term budgeting solutions. Secured sponsorships and strategised marketing via press conferences and social media. Tailed conductor in apprenticeship.

Translator & Editor

2016 BNN, Inc. Publishing Company

Tokyo, Japan

Proofread & translated 100 artist profiles for an illustration showcase book (English & Japanese).

Other Experiences

- Concertmistress, Co-leader, Soloist, & Member of Edinburgh University String, Chamber, & Symphony Orchestras (2019 2023), KPASSP Honour Orchestra & Choir (2015 2019), Show Choir (2015 2019, Chicago Festival of Gold), Vocal Ensemble (Maastricht International Choral Competition 2019), Tokyo Junior Philharmonic (2011 2014)
- National Competition Winner in Violin Performance (Silver Place, AJAA 2015), Gala Concert Performer Qualifier
- Customer Service & Translator for International Diners Club Card Ginza Lounge (2019)
- Translator & Description Curator for Art Exhibitions (2016 2019)

Current Endeavours

- Self-learning data structures and algorithmic paradigms for modelling computational problems
- Expanding React is portfolio website design to archive past projects
- Prototyping an open-source application with a software engineer colleague and mentor
- Experimenting with Langehain API
- Optimising terminal-first workflow & blog-building with Pelican & GitHub

References available upon request.